A Mermaid's Tale is a family film directed by Dustin Rikert.
12-year-old Ryan moves to the town where her father
was born—a bleak, dying fishing town.
However, exploring the coast, she discovers a cove that is home to a
mysterious girl named Coral who reveals herself to be a mermaid.
Matt, played by Jerry O'Connell.
Art, played by Barry Bostwick.
Ryan, played by Caitlin Carmichael.
Thaleia, played by Nancy Stafford.
Jay, played by Ronnie Gene Blevins.
Coral, played by Sydney Scotia.
"The Little Mermaid" (Danish: Den lille havfrue), sometimes translated in English as "The Little Sea
Maid", is a literary fairy tale written by Danish author Hans Christian Andersen.
Originally published in 1837 as part of a collection of fairy tales for children, the story follows the journey of a
young mermaid princess who is willing to give up her life in the sea as a mermaid to gain a human soul.
The original story has been the subject of multiple analyses by scholars such as Jacob
Bøggild and Pernille Heegaard, as well as the folklorist Maria Tatar.
These analyses cover various aspects of the story, from interpreting the themes to
discussing why Andersen chose to write a tragic story with a happy ending.
It has been adapted to various media, including musical
theatre, anime, ballet, opera, and film.
There is also a statue portraying the mermaid in Copenhagen,
Denmark, where the story was written and first published.
The film explores themes of friendship, mermaid, meerjungfrau.
The tone is dark.